<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>左翼读书会</title>
  
  
  <link href="https://maliereaders.tk/rss.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://maliereaders.tk/"/>
  <updated>2021-04-29T03:06:52.655Z</updated>
  <id>https://maliereaders.tk/</id>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>NCP of  the Netherlands, Declaration NCPN and CJB_150 years since the Paris Commune</title>
    <link href="https://maliereaders.tk/%E9%80%9A%E8%AE%AF/b4f52559e564/"/>
    <id>https://maliereaders.tk/%E9%80%9A%E8%AE%AF/b4f52559e564/</id>
    <published>2021-04-29T02:44:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-04-29T03:06:52.655Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="荷兰新共产党，荷新共和荷青年共运的声明：巴黎公社成立150周年"><a href="#荷兰新共产党，荷新共和荷青年共运的声明：巴黎公社成立150周年" class="headerlink" title="荷兰新共产党，荷新共和荷青年共运的声明：巴黎公社成立150周年"></a>荷兰新共产党，荷新共和荷青年共运的声明：巴黎公社成立150周年</h1><p>二零二一年，三月十八日</p><p>一百五十年前，巴黎动荡的街道上，一个真正属于而且是为了工人的革命政权在一八七一年的三月十八日首次成立。工人阶级第一次掌握了权力，并且采取了具有决定性意义的措施来确立一个公平的社会——社会主义。一个完全的工人民主的政府被建立，工人阶级破天荒地第一次能够决定他们怎样去塑造他们的社会。但是，当时的资本主义意识到了公社对其统治的威胁。法国的反动资产阶级政府甚至同它原来的敌人，德国（曾经是普鲁士，不久前法国对其发动过战争）合作发动了对公社的血腥镇压。时至今日，这些历史事件仍然具有着巨大的现实意义。</p><p><strong>巴黎公社的建立</strong></p><p>叛乱的直接原因是法国由于资本家之间的利益冲突而对德国发动的战争。而为了支撑这场战争，法兰西帝国政府已将巴黎人民的财富和血液彻底抽干了。然而，帝国政府却远远低估了这场战争，并且在一切方面都被打败，不断退却。在法国皇帝拿破仑三世被德国人俘虏之后，大资产阶级接管了政权，建立了所谓“国防政府”。与此同时，德国兵锋直指巴黎，巴黎被德国军队层层包围。在那段艰难的被围困的日子里，越来越多的巴黎人开始思考为什么他们应该在这样一场仅由上层统治阶级发动的战争中卖命。那时，巴黎的防御绝大部分由国民自卫军承担，而国民自卫军的士兵则由来自各个大区的正规工人组成，他们是工人中最有觉悟的一部分。</p><p>法国资产阶级政府请求停战，最终与德国人达成了和平条约，该条约却将使许多巴黎市民陷入赤贫。资产阶级希望让工人阶级为战争和赔款买单，而要达成这个目的，就必须首先解除工人的武装。三月十八日，资产阶级向巴黎派遣军队，以期解除工人武装。然而这个尝试失败了，工人阶级组织起来坚持了自己的武装，并且发动了革命。巴黎公社诞生了。</p><p><strong>为了新社会的革命斗争</strong></p><p>巴黎市民们很快地决定要走一条完全同先前的所有政府完全不同的道路，即民主工人政府，这要求他们制定一系列新的社会政策。例如，军队被改组为人民的民兵，实行政教分离与免费教育。颁布一系列法律，禁止面包房夜班；如果工厂主拒绝恢复生产的话，就将工厂交由工人掌控；令所有政府官员的工作报酬均与普通工人相等。像这样，公社致力于创造一个真正完全不同的社会。</p><p>特别值得注意的是妇女在公社中所扮演的角色。在那个性别不平等巨大的年代，巴黎公社将工人阶级的妇女带到了群众政治发展的最前沿。像是同工同酬、离婚权和受教育权以及其他所有类型的妇女权利要求都突然爆发出来并得到了广泛的关注。四月十一日，在公社中起到重要作用的妇女联盟成立。</p><p><strong>公社的倒塌</strong></p><p>可惜的是，新社会的曙光在它得以发展之前就被无情地镇压了。公社部队成功地将政府军赶出了城市，然而他们推翻旧秩序的尝试却不合德国政府的胃口。德国释放了十万名法国战俘，他们立刻怀着感激的心情回到了法国资产阶级政府手下。在这些被释放战俘的增援下，政府军在五月二十一日进入巴黎。随后是一周的血腥战斗，工人们英雄般地在武器和弹药极度缺乏的情况下捍卫街垒。最后一个街垒在五月二十八日倒塌了。资本家们有理由庆祝，而政府军则横冲直撞。至少三万五千人在那一周被杀害，其中包括成千上万的无武装的妇女和儿童。在法国之后的几年中，资产阶级政府采取了严厉的镇压措施，将另外四万人投入监狱，并放逐了数千人。在其它欧洲国家，对工人阶级运动的镇压也加剧了，资本主义已经证明，它不可能不做任何抵抗地从历史舞台上消失。</p><p><strong>巴黎公社的教训</strong></p><p>首先应当考虑的是公社具有的重要意义，因为它第一次显示一个完全不同的社会是真正可能的。在两个月的时间里，它所采取的措施比整个世纪以来社会所采取的措施都要多，都要进步。卡尔·马克思和弗雷德里希·恩格斯在一八六四年共同创立的国际工人协会（也即第一国际）也起到了不可或缺的作用。</p><p>公社的经验告诉我们，一个更美好的社会不会凭空而来，我们需要做好充分的准备，才能取得成功。我们可以从公社的政治和组织弱点中学到很多东西。首先，它做的还远远不够。经济的许多部分没有被国有化，并且公社放任法兰西银行的存在，而这个机构借给了资产阶级政府数百万法郎。公社也没有及时地运用其力量去摧毁资产阶级剥削者的抵抗。之所以发生这种情况，是因为在其他原因之外，有些工人仍在幻想只要首先关注“国家利益”，就能在没有真正结束资本主义的情况下建立公正的社会。</p><p>这些弱点与许多因素有关，其中主要是由于与国际有联系的马克思主义者并不占多数。小资产阶级思潮仍然占上风。例如，批评马克思主义和阶级斗争理论的布朗基主义者颇有影响力。他们认为无产阶级的利益不应与国家（也即，资本家）的利益相脱离。无政府主义之父蒲鲁东的追随者也很有影响力，他们反对资本主义私有制，但同时也反对一切的个人财产。</p><p>公社通过展示资本主义的残酷反应，粉碎了所有关于工人和资本家理论上共同利益的幻想。在一八七一年的那一周，巴黎街头的流血人数超过了法国资产阶级革命的整个“恐怖”时期。公社还教会了我们正确组织的重要性。政府军之所以能击败公社部队，正是因为公社没有足够集中，足够有力地组织起来。</p><p>我们从巴黎公社中得到的最重要的教训是一个由工人组成，并且领导工人的政治组织即共产党是必不可少的。而且必须是一个能够理解阶级斗争的客观规律，并以科学依据与切实可行的策略为基础进行领导的政党。一个必须在工人运动中始终反对资产阶级与小资产阶级思潮，也即，机会主义（改良主义，“左”倾机会主义），影响的政党。</p><p>马克思，恩格斯和列宁从公社中汲取了宝贵的经验。而这从根本上促成了在一九一七年俄国发生革命时，工人成功而且长久地建立了工人的政权这一事实。第一次无产阶级革命只坚持了七十二天，而第二次却存在了七十多年。</p><p>批判性地学习巴黎公社以及整个国际共运的历史和经验并从中得到教训具有十分重要的意义。我们生活在一个工人阶级革命运动仍然十分弱小的时代，但是资本主义却在不断地达到它的极限，并且不可能客服这些极限。劳动人民对建立一个更好的社会，一个没有贫穷、歧视、不安全、剥削与战争的社会，一个所有人都能自由发展的社会的渴望日益增长。荷兰共产主义青年运动和荷兰新共产党的壮大体现了这一点。我们可以而且必须从历史中汲取经验教训，以加强在荷兰和国际上的工人运动与为社会主义和共产主义所进行的斗争。</p><p><strong>公社万岁！</strong></p><p><em>“工人的巴黎及其公社将永远作为新社会的光辉先驱而为人所称颂。它的英烈们已永远铭记在工人阶级的伟大心坎里。那些扼杀它的刽子手们已经被历史永远钉在耻辱柱上，不论他们的教士们怎样祷告也不能把他们解脱。”</em></p><p>——卡尔·马克思（1871）《法兰西内战》</p><p>荷新共和荷青年共运的通讯抄送</p><hr><h1 id="NCP-of-the-Netherlands-Declaration-NCPN-and-CJB-150-years-since-the-Paris-Commune"><a href="#NCP-of-the-Netherlands-Declaration-NCPN-and-CJB-150-years-since-the-Paris-Commune" class="headerlink" title="NCP of the Netherlands, Declaration NCPN and CJB: 150 years since the Paris Commune"></a>NCP of the Netherlands, Declaration NCPN and CJB: 150 years since the Paris Commune</h1><p>March 18, 2021</p><p>A hundred and fifty years ago, on the 18^th^ of March 1871 in the tumultuous streets of Paris, a revolutionary government of and for workers came about for the first time. For the first time, the working class rose to power and took far-reaching measures to establish a fair society – socialism. A fully democratic government of workers was formed, who decided, for the first time in history, how they wanted to shape their society. The capitalist powers at that time, however, recognised the threat this posed for them. The French bourgeois government even worked together with its arch nemesis, Germany (Prussia, against which France had just then waged war), in order to enact a bloody suppression of the socialist experiment. Today, these historical proceedings still have many lessons to teach us.</p><p><strong>How the Paris Commune came to be</strong></p><p>The direct reason for the rebellion which led to the Commune lies in the war against Germany, waged for the interests of competing capitalists. To pay for this war, the government of the French Empire had bled the population of Paris completely dry. The French government, however, severely underestimated the war and lost it on all fronts. Emperor Napoleon III was even captured, after which a bourgeois (capitalist) government took over, forming the ‘Government of National Defence’. Meanwhile, the warfront had reached Paris; the city suffered under a siege by German troops. During the difficult times of the siege, more and more Parisians started wondering why they should fight in wars wrought by the ruling class in the first place. This was strengthened by the fact that the defence of Paris was largely carried by the National Guard. These were units composed of regular workers, hailing from the districts which they defended.</p><p>The French government finally negotiated a peace treaty with the Germans, which would cast many Parisian citizens into a state of abject poverty. The capitalists wanted the working class to carry the burdens of the war and the payments Germany would receive, and to accomplish this, the bourgeois government wanted to disarm the workers. On the 18th of March, the bourgeois government sent the army to disarm the workers, but this failed, as the working class had organised itself and rebelled. The Commune was born.</p><p><strong>Revolutionary struggle for a new society</strong></p><p>The citizens of Paris decided very quickly to tread a radically different path from all thepreceding governments. A democratic workers’ government was chosen, which got to work on a series of social policies. For example, the army was reformed into a people’s militia, church and state were separated and education was made free of charge. Social legislation was enacted, such as forbidding nightshifts in bakeries;control over factories was handed to the workers themselves if their owners refused to resume production; all state officials received compensation for their work equal to that of the average labourer. In this way, the Commune began with the effort to create a truly different society.</p><p>Special attention is due to the role that women played in the Paris Commune. While immense inequality still reigned supreme, the Paris Commune suddenly brought working class women to the forefront of the political developments en masse. Demands such as equal pay, the right to divorce for women, the right to education and all other sorts of women’s rights suddenly gained traction. On April 11th, the Union of Women, which played an important role in the Commune, was formed.</p><p><strong>The downfall</strong></p><p>Sadly, this new beginning was cut down in its infancy. The Communards succeeded in expelling the government troops from the city on March 18th, but their attempt at overthrowing the old order was not to the liking of the German government. It freed 100,000 French prisoners of war, who were gratefully reintegrated into the forces of the French bourgeois government. With these fresh reinforcements, the army entered Paris on May 21st. A week of bloody fighting ensued; workers heroically defended the barricades despite an enormous lack of weapons and ammunition. The final barricade fell on May 28th. The capitalists had cause for celebration, and the army ran amok. Over 35,000 people were murdered that week, among whom thousands of unarmed women and children. The years that followed saw a series of heavily repressive measures, which imprisoned another 40,000 people and banished thousands more. In other European countries too repression against the working-class movement was amped up. Capital had proven that it would not go down quietly.</p><p><strong>Lessons of the Paris Commune</strong></p><p>It is important to consider the significance of the Commune, becauseit first showed that a different society could truly be possible. In two months, it was able to take more steps than society had taken over the span of entire centuries. The International Workingmen’s Association (also known as the First International), co-founded by Karl Marx and Frederick Engels in 1864, played anindispensable role in the Commune.</p><p>The experiences of the Commune teach us that a better society will not come about out of thin air, that it needs to be well-prepared to succeed. We can learn much from the political and organisational weaknesses of the Commune. First of all, it did not go far enough. Many parts of the economy were not socialised and the Commune let the French bank be; this institution then lent millions of francs to the bourgeois government. The Commune also did not use its power to break the resistance of capitalist exploiters in a timely fashion. This happened, among other reasons, because some workers were still under the illusion that a just society could be established without truly ending capitalism, as long as the ‘national interest’ was given prime attention.</p><p>These weaknesses had to do, among other factors, with the fact that Marxists, who were affiliated with the International, were not in the majority. Petit-bourgeois currents still had the upper hand. For instance, the Blanquists, who criticised Marxism and the theory of class struggle, were quite influential. They thought that the interests of the proletariat should not be separated from those of the nation (i.e. the capitalists). Followers of Proudhon, the progenitor of anarchism, also were influential. Against capitalist private property they postulated small private property.</p><p>The Commune shattered all illusions about any theorised shared interests of workers and capitalists by showing how ruthless the capitalist reaction is. In that single week of 1871, the streets of Paris saw more blood than during the entirety of the ‘Terror’ of the French bourgeois revolution. The Commune also teaches us the importance of proper organising, for the capitalist government was able to beat the people’s militias and the people precisely because they were not organised centrally in a strong enough way.</p><p>The most important lesson to be drawn from the Paris Commune is the necessity for a political organisation for and of the working class, the Communist Party. A party capable of comprehending the objective laws of class struggle and of leading on the basis of a scientifically grounded and worked-out strategy. A party which must consistently struggle against the influence of bourgeois and petit-bourgeois ideology in the labour movement, that is to say, against the influence of opportunism (reformism, left-radicalism, etc.).</p><p>Marx, Engels and Lenin drew valuable lessons from the Paris Commune. This fact fundamentally contributed to the fact that in 1917, when revolutionary circumstances occurred in Russia,the working class succeeded in establishing workers’ power. The first proletarian revolution held out for only 72 days, the second for more than 70 years.</p><p>It is of great importance to critically study and learn from the history and the experiences of the Paris Commune and the international communist movement in general. We live in a time in which the revolutionary working class movement is still weak, but capitalism is faced with more and more of its limits. There is a growing yearning among working people for a better society, a society without poverty, discrimination, insecurity, exploitation and war. A society where everyone has the possibility to develop themselves. This is also expressed by the growth of the CJB and NCPN. We can and must draw valuable lessons from history to strengthen,both in the Netherlands and internationally,the labour movement and the struggle for socialism-communism.</p><p><strong>Vive la Commune!</strong></p><p>“*Working men’s Paris, with its Commune, will be forever celebrated as the glorious harbinger of a new society. Its martyrs are enshrined in the great heart of the working class. Its exterminators history has already nailed to that eternal pillory from which all the prayers of their priest will not avail to redeem them.*”</p><p>- Karl Marx (1871), The Civil War in France</p><p>CC of the NCPN</p><p>CC of the CJB</p><hr><p><a href="http://solidnet.org/article/NCP-of-the-Netherlands-Declaration-NCPN-and-CJB-150-years-since-the-Paris-Commune/">Solidnet | NCP of the Netherlands, Declaration NCPN and CJB: 150 years since the Paris Commune</a></p><p>译：Schwarzkopf Henkal</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;荷兰新共产党，荷新共和荷青年共运的声明：巴黎公社成立150周年&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#荷兰新共产党，荷新共和荷青年共运的声明：巴黎公社成立150周年&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;荷兰新共产党，荷新共和荷青年共运的声明：巴黎公社成立150周年&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;荷兰新共产党，荷新共和荷青年共运的声明：巴黎公社成立150周年&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;二零二一年，三月十八日&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一百五十年前，巴黎动荡的街道上，一个真正属于而且是为了工人的革命政权在一八七一年的三月十八日首次成立。工人阶级第一次掌握了权力，并且采取了具有决定性意义的措施来确立一个公平的社会——社会主义。一个完全的工人民主的政府被建立，工人阶级破天荒地第一次能够决定他们怎样去塑造他们的社会。但是，当时的资本主义意识到了公社对其统治的威胁。法国的反动资产阶级政府甚至同它原来的敌人，德国（曾经是普鲁士，不久前法国对其发动过战争）合作发动了对公社的血腥镇压。时至今日，这些历史事件仍然具有着巨大的现实意义。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;巴黎公社的建立&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;叛乱的直接原因是法国由于资本家之间的利益冲突而对德国发动的战争。而为了支撑这场战争，法兰西帝国政府已将巴黎人民的财富和血液彻底抽干了。然而，帝国政府却远远低估了这场战争，并且在一切方面都被打败，不断退却。在法国皇帝拿破仑三世被德国人俘虏之后，大资产阶级接管了政权，建立了所谓“国防政府”。与此同时，德国兵锋直指巴黎，巴黎被德国军队层层包围。在那段艰难的被围困的日子里，越来越多的巴黎人开始思考为什么他们应该在这样一场仅由上层统治阶级发动的战争中卖命。那时，巴黎的防御绝大部分由国民自卫军承担，而国民自卫军的士兵则由来自各个大区的正规工人组成，他们是工人中最有觉悟的一部分。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;法国资产阶级政府请求停战，最终</summary>
      
    
    
    
    <category term="通讯" scheme="https://maliereaders.tk/categories/%E9%80%9A%E8%AE%AF/"/>
    
    
    <category term="欧洲" scheme="https://maliereaders.tk/tags/%E6%AC%A7%E6%B4%B2/"/>
    
    <category term="共产党和工人党" scheme="https://maliereaders.tk/tags/%E5%85%B1%E4%BA%A7%E5%85%9A%E5%92%8C%E5%B7%A5%E4%BA%BA%E5%85%9A/"/>
    
    <category term="荷兰-荷兰新共产党" scheme="https://maliereaders.tk/tags/%E8%8D%B7%E5%85%B0-%E8%8D%B7%E5%85%B0%E6%96%B0%E5%85%B1%E4%BA%A7%E5%85%9A/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="https://maliereaders.tk/uncategorized/230e1b21e212/"/>
    <id>https://maliereaders.tk/uncategorized/230e1b21e212/</id>
    <published>2021-04-26T13:07:29.479Z</published>
    <updated>2021-04-26T13:07:29.479Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a href="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html">troubleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues">GitHub</a>.</p><h2 id="Quick-Start"><a href="#Quick-Start" class="headerlink" title="Quick Start"></a>Quick Start</h2><h3 id="Create-a-new-post"><a href="#Create-a-new-post" class="headerlink" title="Create a new post"></a>Create a new post</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo new <span class="string">&quot;My New Post&quot;</span></span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html">Writing</a></p><h3 id="Run-server"><a href="#Run-server" class="headerlink" title="Run server"></a>Run server</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo server</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html">Server</a></p><h3 id="Generate-static-files"><a href="#Generate-static-files" class="headerlink" title="Generate static files"></a>Generate static files</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo generate</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html">Generating</a></p><h3 id="Deploy-to-remote-sites"><a href="#Deploy-to-remote-sites" class="headerlink" title="Deploy to remote sites"></a>Deploy to remote sites</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ hexo deploy</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/one-command-deployment.html">Deployment</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/&quot;&gt;Hexo&lt;/a&gt;! This is your very first post. Check &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/docs/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html&quot;&gt;troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt; or you can ask me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Quick-Start&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Quick-Start&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Quick Start&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Quick Start&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;Create-a-new-post&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Create-a-new-post&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Create a new post&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Create a new post&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight bash&quot;&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;gutter&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;line&quot;&gt;$ hexo new &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;My New</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
